Ali MASRI

DATE OF BIRTH:

7 Feb 1991

CONTACT

Nationality: Lebanese

Gender: Male

Versailles, France

alimasri1991@gmail.com

(+1) 3203175412

alimasri.github.io

Skype: skype

ABOUT ME

I am a Research and Development Engineer dedicated to the field of Big Data and Artificial Intelligence. I have strong research and professional background with a Ph.D. degree in Computer Science from the University of Paris-Saclay and VEDECOM institute. In the domain of data science, I provide R&D services, consultancy services, and data science training.

WORK EXPERIENCE

1 NOV 2017 - CURRENT - Paris, France

Research and Development Engineer

Cognitus/Intelligencia

- Lead the Data Science team by monitoring and developing various Al and Big Data projects.
- Help customers optimize/upgrade architectures/pipelines by bringing in new Big Data and Al solutions.
- Provide enterprise data science training to help customers build their own data science teams.

www.cognitus.fr | Paris, France

2015 - 2017

Researcher

VEDECOM

- Research on transportation multimodality for smart cities
- Proposed a new model to make multimodality easier to implement and maintain
- Proposed a three-level integration solution on schema level, data level, and services level
- Implemented many software libraries as multimodal integration solutions
- Published many articles in international conferences and journals

www.vedecom.fr | Versailles, France

JAN 2016 - DEC 2016

Backend and Mobile Developer - JAX-RS, Struts2, AndroidLogixy

- Designed and implemented the database and the business process for an Intelligent Transport Management System
- Helped the company adopting a service oriented architecture
- Implemented a web and mobile application for the user interface

Paris, France

JUN 2015 - DEC 2015

Java Developer

3iConsulting

- Maintained and solved many bugs in a pre-built production solution
- Made the product easier by developing many helper tools

Palaiseau, France

JUN 2015 - DEC 2015

PHP Developer

Nouvelle Génération Médicale (NGM)

 Increased the association popularity by creating and maintaining a website + blog for the French association "Nouvelle Génération Médicale (NGM)"

Paris, France

FEB 2014 - JUL 2014

Research and Development

UVSQ and 3iConsulting

- Professional part of my master thesis in supply chain management and service oriented architecture
- Helped the company in adopting a service oriented architecture by designing and implementing the new solution

Versailles, France

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Paris, France

Ph. D. in Computer Science

Université Paris-Saclay

Beirut, Lebanon

Masters in Information and Decision Support Systems

Lebanese University Faculty of Sciences

Beirut, Lebanon

Bachelors Degree in Computer Science

Lebanese University Faculty of Sciences

LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Arabic

English

Listening C2	Reading C2	Spoken production C1	Spoken interaction C1	Writing C1
French				
Listening A2	Reading A2	Spoken production A2	Spoken interaction A2	Writing A2

DIGITAL SKILLS

JAVA | Python | Apache Spark | Deep Learning | Machine Learning | Git | Linux | R elational and Non-Relational Databases

DRIVING LICENCE



HONOURS AND AWARDS



Honours and awards

• Placed 4th in the Lebanese Collegiate Programming Competition

CERTIFICATIONS



Certifications

- IBM Data Science Specialization
- Deep Learning Specialization by deeplearning.ai
- Machine Learning by Standford University on Coursera
- Google Developer Certification Associate Android Developer

ONLINE PUBLICATIONS



Online Publications

I like writing about various data science concepts in intuitive ways for the public. After some introductory courses I had the honor to write for many online publications:

- Towards Data Science
- Heartbeat
- The Startup
- Marktechpost

A compilation of my articles can be found on my blog: http://alimasri.github.io

RESEARCH PUBLICATIONS



Research Publications

- Ali Masri. Multi-Network integration for an Intelligent Mobility. Ph.D. Thesis.
- Ali Masri, Karine Zeitouni and Zoubida Kedad. Retry: Integrating ridesharing with existing trip planners. SIGSPATIAL2017
- Ali Masri, Karine Zeitouni, Zoubida Kedad and Bertrand Leroy. An Automatic Matcher and Linker for Transportation Datasets. ISPRS2017
- Ali Masri, Karine Zeitouni, Zoubida Kedad and Bertrand Leroy.
 Automatic Detection and Mapping of Geospatial Properties in Transportation Data Sources. SIGSPATIAL2016
- Ali Masri, Karine Zeitouni, Zoubida Kedad, Bertrand Leroy and Gabriel Kepeklian. Discovering Multimodal Routes using Connection Patterns. ITSC2016
- Ali Masri, Karine Zeitouni, Zoubida Kedad and Gabriel Kepeklian. Link++: A flexible and customizable tool for connecting RDF data sources. ESWC2016
- Fatima Abdallah, Hassan Sbeyti, Ali Masri, Malak Khreis, Hussein Hazimeh, Mohamed Dbouk, and Ahmad Fadlallah: unified Sensor interface for Context-Aware Mobile aPplications (SCAMP). The Lebanese Association of Advanced Sciences LAAS20
- Hamid Mcheick, Raef Mousheimish, Ali Masri, Youssef Dergham: Context Aware Collaborative Computing Model for Natural Disaster Management Systems. HCI (21) 2014: 439-449